SHIKHAR GUPTA

+1 (602)-515-5356 • sgupt330@asu.edu • www.linkedin.com/in/shikhar-gupta-430372134 • https://github.com/Shikhar97

SUMMARY

I am a graduate student pursuing Masters in Computer Science at Arizona State University. I have worked as a Software Engineer at Aruba Networks for 3 years as a full-stack developer and I am well-versed in Python, C++, Docker, Kubernetes, ML frameworks, and Linux along with an in-depth understanding of SQL/NoSQL databases software systems.

EDUCATION

M.S. Computer Science, Artificial Intelligence

Arizona State University, Tempe, Arizona

08/2022 - Present GPA: 4.00

B.S. Computer Science

PES University, Bangalore, India

08/2015 - 05/2019 GPA: 3.74

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Machine Learning and AI Expertise: NLP (Natural Language Processing), Computer Vision, Transform Learning

Programming Languages and Libraries: Python, C++, Bash, PyTorch, NumPy, Pandas, NLTK **Front-End:** HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, D3.js, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, Node.js, AngularJS, React.js

Tools and Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, RocksDB, Kafka, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, Azure, OpenStack

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer II at Aruba Networks, a Hewlett Packard Enterprise

01/2019 - 07/2022

Responsible for developing solutions to help debug over 100+ bugs and accelerate testing and development of the product to reduce the person-hours by 80%.

- Designed and developed a RESTApi Load Testing tool using **Python** and **JMeter** in a multithreaded environment that helped increase the performance of the product by 10%.
- Developed a tool to deploy virtual machines using **Python, Docker and Kubernetes** on KVM, Hyper-V, ESXi, Microsoft Azure and on **AWS** using **EC2, S3, CloudWatch and VPC**.
- Designed and developed a cross-platform GUI based testing tool using Python, OpenCV, and HTML/CSS/JS.

Summer Intern at Stylumia Intelligence Technology Pvt. Ltd.

06/2018 - 08/2018

- Developed an algorithm using **Tries** and integrated with **Elasticsearch's** autocorrection for a real-time autocompletion search bar that helped decrease the time to search for a product.
- Developed a State-of-the-Art NLP Algorithm for accurate classification of various types of products.

PROJECTS

Automated Visualization Generation using GPT-3 and Vega-Lite

01/2023 - 05/2023

• Developed an automated system that generates high-quality visualizations based on user requirements utilizing GPT-3, ChatGPT and VegaLite.

Scaling Graph Processing with Kubernetes, Kafka, and Neo4j

01/2023 - 05/2023

• Developed a scalable and highly available data processing pipeline capable of processing a continuous stream of documents using Neo4j, Docker, Kafka, and Kubernetes.

Medical Image Analysis using Machine Learning: Enhancing Disease Diagnosis

01/2023 - 05/2023

• Created image classification, segmentation, and localization models for polyps, abnormalities in chest X-rays and pulmonary embolisms using **ResNet** and **Swin Transformers**.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Intern at CCBD (Cloud Computing and Big Data), PES University

06/2017 - 06/2018

• Worked on **OpenStack** and developed a middleware for object storage (Swift) and the orchestration unit (Heat) and published "Orchestration Based Hybrid or Multi Clouds and Interoperability Standardization" at IEEE CCEM (2018).